Guide to the Hall of Graduate Studies, Yale University, Photographs
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Hall of Graduate Studies, Yale University, photographs
1930-1979
RU 623
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3.29
The collection contains photographs documenting the construction of the Hall of Graduate Studies at Yale. Included are interior and exterior views.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 46-B (YRG 46-B), Records and materials documenting individual Yale buildings, facilities, and grounds.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged in three series: I. Construction Progress Photographs, 1930-1932. II. General Views, 1932-1979. III. Oversize, slides, and transparencies.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains photographs documenting the construction of the Hall of Graduate Studies at Yale. Included are interior and exterior views.
College buildings -- Design and construction; Photographs; Slides (photographs); Yale University -- Pictorial works; Yale University -- Buildings
- Construction progress photographs, 1930-1932; Series I
  - 1930 Jun: site, pre-construction (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1930 Nov-Dec (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1931 Jan-Feb (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1931 Mar-Apr (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1931 May-Jun (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1931 July-Aug (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1931 Sep-Oct (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1931 Nov-Dec (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1932 Jan: exterior views (Box 1, Folder 9)
- General views, 1932-1979; Series II
  - Exterior front, circa 1935, undated (Box 2, Folder 1 - 2)
  - Exterior, general (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Courtyard views, 1936-1979, undated (Box 2, Folder 4 - 5)
  - Archways, 1932-1937, n.d (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Interior, 1932, 1959, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 7 - 10)
  - Architect's drawing, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Architectural details (drawings)
    - Gable kneeler (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Cornice (by Wesley Needham) (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Niche between windows (by A. van Riper) (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Oversize, slides, and transparencies, Series III
  - Oversize
    - Hall of Graduate Studies (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Under Construction, 1931-1932 (Box 3, Folder 2-4)
  - Slides (Box 4)
  - Transparencies (Box 5)